Guide to the Frank Durkan Papers AIA.008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI. Oversize Items, 328432
  - New York Newsday: " "Noraid's Troubles: Michael Flannery, the founder of America's Irish Northern Aid Committee has withdrawn from the organization in a dispute over how best to support the fight for a united Ireland.", Nov 7, 1989; 328437 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - New York Times Magazine: "The Troubles That Won't Go Away" by John Lloyd., Dec 12, 1999; 328434 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Saoirse "Irish Freedom" isues: Jun, Sep 1994, Feb 1995, Aug 1999, 1994-1999; 328435 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Sunday Tribune: "Towards the New Ireland"; Sunday Times: "Ireland's Future: Resurrection?, Apr 12, 1998; 328438 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Audio Visual Materials, 326785
  This series contains both commercial and private tapings. Cassettes must be reformated for access. Of note are two cassettes related of to Ruari O'Bradiagh: one an interview in 1977; the other pertaining to his visa denial in 1995.
  The VHS contain among others, interviews with Gerry Adams in Florida, a compilation of documentarys including one of the Guildford Fourt and the Birmingham Six and a film of a reunion of Spanish Civil War veterans in Barcelon, from George Harrison.
  - Subseries A: Cassettes, 328777
    - Brady, Sean: Free the Six. Brady Records, London. Side 1: Free the Six, Belfast Town, Grace, Leaving of Liverpool, Tommy Atkins; Side 2: My Green Valleys, Take it Down from the Mast, Tom Williams, Boston I Need You, British Justice, 1987; cuid33377; 328779 (Box 28A, Cassette 1)
    - The History of the Irish Republican Movement F.O.I.F., undated; cuid33378; 328780 (Box 28A, Cassette 2)
    - O'Bradiagh, Ruairi (approximately 14 minutes), Sep 2, 1997; cuid33379; 328781 (Box 28A, Cassette 3)
  - Subseries B: VHS, 328778
    - Ballyseedy (Co. Kerry), undated; cuid33380; 328917 (Box 27, Object 1)
    - The Committee - Dispatches, Channel 4. Includes note "Frank, This is the tape I spoke to you about. I would like to hear your commments. Owen", undated; cuid33381; 328916 (Box 27, Object 2)
    - Committee on Justice Equality Defence and Women's Rights. Broadcasting Unit, Houses of the Oireachtas, Leinster House, Dublin 2., Jan 28, 2004; cuid33382; 328918 (Box 28A, Object 4)
    - Curious Journey: The Fight for Irish Freedom. International Digital Centre, Inc., New York, undated; cuid33383; 328919 (Box 27, Object 3)
    - Events in Short Strand houses being attacked; John Reid Visit Cruncher Singing, May 2002 - Aug 2002; cuid33384; 328920 (Box 27, Object 4)
    - "First Tuesday" A documentary on the Guildford Four; "Innocent or Guilty" A Documentary on the Birmingham Six; "Dear Sarah" A film. "Who Bombed Birmingham?" A film. "This tape has been digitally transferred and/or professionally dpulicated by Hennessy Headquarters D/B/A Irish Video, 5824 Broadway, NY 212-601-3833", undated; cuid33385; 328921 (Box 27, Object 5)
    - BBC Program (3 tapes) IDC, undated; cuid33386; 328922 (Box 28, Object 10-12)
    - Frontline: "Behind the Mask: The IRA and Sinn Fein" FROL603, 60 min. (3 copies), undated; cuid33387; 328923 (Box 27, Object 6-8)
    - Gerry Adams in South Florida Parts 1 and 2 (first copy), May 1996; cuid33388; 328925 (Box 27, Object 9-10)
    - Gerry Adams in South Florida Part 1 and 2 (second copy), May 1996; cuid33389; 328924 (Box 28, Object 1-2)
    - Interview with Caroline Moore of Derry City. Conducted by Mr. Kevin Harris, Attorney at Law. Merriam, Kansas. Includes note: Dear Frank: We are sending you this taped interview of Caroline Mooore who describes life in Northern Ireland Under the pressures of the security forces. We hope that it will be useful to you in your review of the police services. Your truly, Andy Somers" Irish American Unity Conference, National Office, DC, Feb 21, 1999; cuid33390; 328926 (Box 28, Object 3)
    - ITV's "Dispatches" Channel #4; Broadcast, approx 27 min, Feb 4, 1999; cuid33391; 328927 (Box 28, Object 4)
    - Panorama, Jun 21, 1999; cuid33392; 328928 (Box 28, Object 5)
    - Paul O'Dwyar [sic] R.I.P., undated; cuid33393; 328929 (Box 28, Object 6, Box Digitized Access Files, File aia008_cuid33393)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 102 min.
    - Spanish Civil War Reunion in Barcelona. G.H. (George Harrison), undated; cuid33394; 328930 (Box 28, Object 7, Box Digitized Access Files, File aia008_cuid33394)
      Duration: 51 min.
    - Think About Tomorrow: Amnesty International's Student Action. Narrated by Corey Glover. AI Student Action Office, Washington DC, undated; cuid33395; 328931 (Box 28, Object 9)
    - Mayo 1951-1959: Mayo's Historic Return to an All-Ireland Final. An RTE Production., 1989; cuid33396; 328932 (Box 28A, Object 5)